Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Harry Clark Papers, 1945-1992 and undated RL.00695
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Frankfurt Office, 1970-1973, 8 boxes
  - Correspondence
    - Allgemein
      - Internal, 1970-1973, 1-7 of 8 folders (Box 16)
      - Internal, 1970-1973 (continued), 8 of 8 folders (Box 17)
    - Memoranda, 1973
      - Peter Dunham (Box 17)
      - Don Johnston (Box 17)
      - Myron R. May (Box 17)
      - [Newsletters memoranda removed to Newsletter Collection.] (Box 17)
  - International Offices
    Comprised primarily of correspondence between Harry Clark and account supervisors in other J. Walter Thompson Company offices. The majority of items relate to the offices in London and New York. The communication with New York provides general insight into the exchange of information about clients. Extensive information is provided about Clark's visits in New York, the United States travel service (1973), Sony video tape recorders (1973), and the International Basic Economy Corporation (1973). The correspondence with the London Office provides an exchange of memoranda and reports about issues with international clients including information about Reed International, the Braun account, and consumer attitudes to the soap Fa (Unilever) in Germany (1973). Correspondents include David Campbell-Harris (Milan), Constance B. Ivie (New York), Don Johnston (London and New York), Denis Lanigan (London), Julian Morrison (Chicago), Anthony Rau (London), Al Stridsberg (New York).
    - Amsterdam, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
    - Bombay, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
    - Brussels, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
    - Buenos Aires, 1973 (Box 17)
    - Chicago, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
    - Copenhagen, 1972 (Box 17)
    - Detroit, 1973 (Box 17)
    - Johannesburg, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
    - London, 1972-1973, 5 folders (Box 17)
    - Milan, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
    - New York, 1971-1973, 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Paris, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
    - San Francisco, 1973 (Box 18)
    - Sao Paulo, 1972 (Box 18)
    - Stockholm, 1972 (Box 18)
    - Sydney, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
    - Tokyo, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
    - Toronto, 1973 (Box 18)
    - Vienna, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
    - Zurich, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
  - New Business, 1971
    Provides insight into JWT-Frankfurt's efforts to gain new clients. Documented are first contacts with prospective clients, market analyses, and information requests to JWT Offices that have already worked for the client or for other clients in the same market field. It should be noted that this series contains new business campaigns only for clients that JWT did not obtain. Among the courted clients are B.A.S.F., Commerzbank, Manpower, Red Barn Restaurants, Ranks Hovis McDougall-Foods, and the Württembergische Metallwarenfabrik.
    - New business files, A-Z, 3 folders (Box 18)
- International Offices, 1967-1986, 7 boxes
  Includes correspondence, financial reviews, marketing plans, meeting reports, travel documentation, presentation files, as well as general administrative memoranda for JWT's international offices. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically by region, country or city, depending on the original designation.
  - General International Files
    Contains files relating to JWT international offices in general, and not to specific offices.
    - Adweek Video Reports presentation, 1986 (Box 18)
    - European Capabilities presentation, 1978 (Box 18)
    - Global marketing, 1987 (Box 18)
    - International area renovation, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
    - International Management Group memoranda, 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - International presentation, 1973 (Box 19)
    - International service for clients, 1974 (Box 19)
    - International slide presentation, 1974 (Box 19)
    - Don Johnston international presentation, 1974 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous information, 1974 (Box 19)
    - Multinationals, background, 1983-1985 (Box 19)
  - Amsterdam, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Bombay, 1974 (Box 19)
  - Brussels
    - General, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Hardselling the Software: Some Interesting Opportunities for JWT, 1974 (Box 19)
    - Long Term Policies and Objectives, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Buenos Aires, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Caracas, 1974-1975, 1 of 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Caracas, 1974-1975 (continued), 2 of 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Central America, 1974-1975 (Box 20)
  - Chile, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Copenhagen, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Europe
    - Economic Background and Progress Report, 1975 (Box 20)
    - Progress Report and Preliminary Planning, 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - Top 10 European Agencies, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Frankfurt
    - General, 1973-1975, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Annual Marketing Report, 1967 (Box 20)
    - Ausbildung, 1974 (Box 20)
    - Planungsberater, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Greece
    - General, 1974-1975, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Background information, 1975 (Box 21)
    - Greece Again report, 1975 (Box 21)
    - Main Future considerations, 1975 (Box 21)
  - Guatemala, 1975 (Box 21)
  - Indonesia, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Italy, 1971-1973, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Jakarta, 1975 (Box 21)
  - Johannesburg, 1973-1975, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Korea, Opportunities for JWT in Korea, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Kuala Lumpur, 1975 (Box 21)
  - Latin America, Andean Pact, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Lima
    - General, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - New business procedures, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Lisbon
    - General, 1973-1975, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - JWT Expansion in the Seventies, 1973 (Box 21)
  - London
    - General, 1973-1975, 1 of 6 folders (Box 21)
    - General, 1973-1976 (continued), 2-6 of 6 folders (Box 22)
    - Annual Marketing Plan, 1973 (Box 22)
    - Elvira Bruhnsen file, 1974 (Box 22)
    - Employee satisfaction research, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Five Year Plan, 1972 (Box 22)
    - Honda: Social Acceptance in Europe, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Lease, 1975 (Box 23)
    - London office announcement, 1975 (Box 23)
    - London office presentation, 1969 (Box 23)
    - New business chart, 1971 (Box 23)
    - Review of Communications and Communications Plan, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Sales Promotion and New Products in Great Britain, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Madrid, 1974-1975 (Box 23)
  - Malaysia, 1974-1975 (Box 23)
  - Manila
    - General, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Five Year Plan, 1974-1978 (Box 23)
  - Mexico City
    - General, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Financial Review, 1973 (Box 23)
  - Middle East, Project Middle East, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Milan, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Montevideo, 1974 (Box 23)
  - New Holland, 1976 (Box 23)
  - New Zealand, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Paris, 1974-1975 (Box 23)
  - Rio de Janeiro, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Salisbury, 1974 (Box 23)
  - San Juan, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Sao Paulo
    - General, 1975-1976 (Box 23)
    - Financial review, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Stockholm, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Sydney, 1974-1975 (Box 23)
  - Tehran
    - General, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Project Iran: Report on Preliminary Visit, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Tokyo, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Toronto, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Turkey, 1975 (Box 24)
  - Vienna, 1973, 1975, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Zurich, 1974 (Box 24)
- Meetings, 1973-1987, 3 boxes
  Contains charts, presentation scripts, memoranda and logistical information, and notes pertaining to various JWT meetings and general advertising events. Includes extensive information and memorabilia regarding the 1984 Worldwide Advertising Meeting at the Epcot Center. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically by meeting title.
  - Advertising Age International Seminar, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Advertising Management Group
    - Group meeting, 1986, May (Box 24)
    - Projects, 1984-1985 (Box 24)
  - American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA) Management Seminar, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Annual meeting, 1976
    - Memoranda (Box 24)
    - Transcript (Box 24)
  - Chicago Seminar, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence Course, Europe, 1975 (Box 24)
  - European Managers Group Meetings
    - General, 1969-1973 (Box 24)
    - 1973, Austria (Box 24)
    - 1973, Brussels (Box 24)
    - 1974, London (Box 25)
    - 1975, Barcelona (Box 25)
    - 1975, London (Box 25)
    - 1975, Vienna (Box 25)
  - European Planning Group
    - Committee meeting: International Group Network Presentation, 1974 (Box 25)
    - 1978, general, 4 folders (Box 25)
  - Fifth European Management Symposium, 1975 (Box 25)
  - Future of the Advertising Agency Research Function Symposium, 1974 (Box 25)
  - International Management and Development Institute, 1974 (Box 25)
  - International Training Seminars, 1980-1982 (Box 25)
  - JWT Research Conference, 1975, Oct. (Box 25)
  - Management Board Meeting on Management Succession, 1986, Mar. (Box 25)
  - Noordwijk Seminar, 1975 (Box 25)
    [Includes reports on dishwashing liquids campaigns.]
  - North American Meeting, 1975, Sept. (Box 25)
  - Presentation Workshop, Brazil, undated (Box 25)
  - Project Galaxia Master Book, 1987, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Unilever Innovations Conference, 1987 (Box 26)
  - World Advertising Forum, 1984, 2 folders (Box 26)
    [Includes slides of events, as well as musical score of the JWT Song. Audio cassettes removed to Audiovisual Materials.]
  - Worldwide Managers Meeting, 1978, Apr. (Box 26)
- New Business, 1964-1988, 2 boxes
  Contains presentations, plans, meeting files, and marketing plans related to JWT new accounts prospects. Includes scripts of general agency presentations, target plans (T-plans), and new business reports from specific JWT offices. Original folder titles were maintained and items arranged alphabetically.
  - Account planning, 1982 (Box 26)
  - Brand Strategy and Creative Brief, blank forms, undated (Box 26)
  - Barry Clark, T-Plan slides, undated (Box 26)
  - Guide to the T-Plan: Developing Effective Advertising Strategies, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous presentations, 1988, 1 of 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous presentations, 1988 (continued), 2 of 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous slides, undated (Box 27)
  - New business communications, 1975 (Box 27)
  - New business, Leadmen Status Report, 1975 (Box 27)
  - New business memoranda, 1975 (Box 27)
  - New York Management T-Plan, 1984, 1987 (Box 27)
  - New York Office slides, undated (Box 27)
  - Planning Advertising at JWT New York, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Planning Guide, 1974 (Box 27)
  - Planning materials, 1964-1986 (Box 27)
  - Positioning Strategy, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Thompson Way slide presentation, 1988 (Box 27)
  - T-Plans
    - General, 1980 (Box 27)
    - London Office, 1964 (Box 27)
    - New York Office, undated (Box 27)
- Reports, 1974-1981, 2 boxes
  Contains annual reports and operations reviews documenting the financial and organizational performance of JWT domestic and international offices. Also includes statistics on billings, expenditures, profits and overall personnel performance. Arranged alphabetically by report title.
  - Advertising Age Billings Report, 1976 (Box 27)
  - Annual Report materials, 1975-1976 (Box 28)
  - Decimalization of Currency in Great Britain, Harvard study, 1975 (Box 28)
  - Development of Men at JWT, 1966 (Box 28)
  - Effect of Current and Future Economic Developments on Advertising and Marketing, 1974 (Box 28)
  - European Advertising and Operating Report, 1978, Oct. (Box 28)
  - Executive Summary, 1976 (Box 28)
  - Fourth Quarter Increases, 1974 (Box 28)
  - International Bank Advertising report, 1975 (Box 28)
  - JWT target study, 1975 (Box 28)
  - Manager's Monthly Assessment, 1975, Sept. (Box 28)
  - McKinsey study, 1975 (Box 28)
  - New York Advertising, payments and losses, 1980-1981 (Box 28)
  - Study of the Reputation: JWT Co., 1975 (Box 28)
  - Summary of 1976 Research and Development Activities, 1977
    - London (Box 28)
    - New York, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Toronto and other offices (Box 29)
- Writings and Speeches, 1964-1992, 4 boxes
  Includes primarily printed texts of speeches given by Clark and other JWT advertising executives. Also includes reprints of articles, reports, along with Clark's book manuscript, entitled Collective Experience. Topics include general trends in advertising and marketing, specific themes related to JWT's policies and philosophies, year-end reports, specific marketing strategies. Notable individuals represented include Rena Bartos, Jeremy Bullmore, Colin Dawkins, Don Johnston, Stephen King, Denis Lanigan, Dan Seymour, and James Webb Young. Items arranged alphabetically by speech title.
  - Account Planning: A Personal View, J. Bullmore, 1978 (Box 29)
  - Advertising and the Role of Direct Marketing Today: An Overview, J. Bullmore, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Agency Management Succession, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Ain't it Hell on a Windy Day: Some Roots of the JWT Co. with Commentary by Colin Dawkins, 1981, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Archimedes and the Efficacy of Prayer, J. Bullmore, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Article of Federation, D. Johnston, 1975 (Box 29)
  - Authority: Marketing's Magic Ingredient?, J. Bullmore, 1981 (Box 29)
  - Become the Leading International Advertising Agency: A Plan, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Best from Around the World," J. Bullmore, 1976 (Box 29)
  - Britain Through the Eyes of Its Advertising, J. Bullmore, 1977 (Box 29)
  - British Admen Know People Better than Politicians, J. Bullmore, 1977 (Box 29)
  - J. Bullmore writings file, 1970-1991 (Box 29)
  - Can T.V. Programmes and Advertising Live Happily Together?, J. Bullmore, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Chicago Ad Club speech, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Collective Experience manuscript, H. Clark, undated, 1 of 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Collective Experience manuscript, H. Clark, undated (continued), 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Consumer Has a Mind As Well As a Stomach, J. Bullmore, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Consumer in Crisis booklet, 1975 (Box 30)
  - Creative Responsibility, J. Bullmore, 1970 (Box 30)
  - Creativity in International Advertising, J. Bullmore, 1969 (Box 30)
  - Adventures in the Ad Game manuscript, C. Dawkins, 1986-1987 (Box 30)
  - Differences Between Male and Female Attitudes Toward Work, T. Atkinson, 1983 (Box 30)
  - Ethics in Advertising speech, 1985 (Box 30)
  - European Managers Meeting speech, R. Burns, 1992 (Box 30)
  - Eyes on Thompson video and essay, D. Seymour, 1975 (Box 30)
  - Food, People and Advertising, J. Bullmore, circa 1981 (Box 30)
  - Ford Dealers Advertising Fund speech, D. Johnston, 1985 (Box 30)
  - Getting Explicit About the Implicit, J. Bullmore, 1985 (Box 30)
  - Globalization of Markets, T. Levitt, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Happy Guy Fawkes Day, D. Campbell-Harris, 1982 (Box 30)
  - Hidden Values of Advertising, J. Bullmore, 1980 (Box 30)
  - H.M. Government Warning: Persuasion Can Seriously Damage Your Health, J. Bullmore, 1978 (Box 30)
  - How Are These Clients Coordinated or Organized on a Multinational Level?, J. Cronin, 1983 (Box 30)
  - How to Become an Advertising Man or Woman and Other Sundry Topics, D. Johnston, 1986 (Box 31)
  - How to Drive Brands Globally: Achieving Consistency in Planning Brand Strategies, undated (Box 31)
  - How JWT Stays Top, T. Lester, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Humor and Advertising, J. Bullmore, 1971 (Box 31)
  - If I Were...An Advertising Manager, J. Bullmore, 1969 (Box 31)
  - I-Group Network text, 1975, Aug. (Box 31)
  - Improving Advertising Decisions, S. King, 1977 (Box 31)
  - Industrial Marketing article, 1974 (Box 31)
  - International Advertising Association
    - General, speech, 1974 (Box 31)
    - Mid-American Chapter speech, 1975 (Box 31)
  - International Advertising
    - Consumers: The Moving Targets, R. Bartos, 1984 (Box 31)
    - T. Gushee speech, 1974 (Box 31)
    - Project speeches, 1985-1986 (Box 31)
  - It's a Long Way Down to the Creative Department, D. Lanigan, 1986 (Box 31)
  - JWT: Evolution of an Owl to a Hawk, D. Robertson, 1983 (Box 31)
  - JWT Roots project, 1986-1988 (Box 31)
    [Includes speech: JWT a Legend in His Own Time, M. Howington, 1988.]
  - Key Biscayne remarks, W.E. LaMothe, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Listening Globally, Administrative Management Society, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Look at the Company You Have Joined, D. Johnston trainee speech, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Marketing in the Global Village, D. Johnston, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Marketing Society speech, J. Bullmore, 1973 (Box 31)
  - Marketing to the Pacific Rim, R. Bartos, 1985 (Box 31)
  - My Plans for JWT, D. Johnston, 1975 (Box 31)
  - Next Decade: Jerry Bullmore on Agencies, J. Bullmore, 1976 (Box 31)
  - Planning Advertising at JWT, 1986, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Planning Cycle: Developing Effective Advertising Strategies, 1985 (Box 31)
  - Primer of Capitalism Illustrated, 1975 (Box 32)
  - Research for Advertising: How We See It, 1974 (Box 32)
  - Role and Function of the International Leadman, 1978, May (Box 32)
  - Satellite Wars: The Brand Strikes Back, J. Bullmore, 1981 (Box 32)
  - Some Basic Roots of the JWT Company, undated (Box 32)
  - Some Things I Have Found to be Important, D. Lanigan, 1986 (Box 32)
  - Some Things I Learned at Landsdowne, 1984 (Box 32)
  - Some Things We Believe in at JWT, D. Robertson, 1985 (Box 32)
  - Some Things We Have Learned About Managing a JWT Office
    - Accounts version, 1985 (Box 32)
    - Management version, 1984-1985 (Box 32)
  - Some Things We Have Learned About Starting New Agencies, 1985 (Box 32)
  - Some Unconventional Beliefs About Publicity, undated, 2 folders (Box 32)
    [In Spanish.]
  - Soul of a Company, B. Manning, 1988 (Box 32)
  - Ten Tried-and-Tested methods of Getting the Least from Your Advertising Agency, J. Bullmore, 1978 (Box 32)
  - Time Jerry Bullmore Took on the World, and Lost, J. Bullmore, undated (Box 32)
  - Towards Increased Flexibility in Compensation Arrangements, 1975 (Box 32)
  - Understanding Buyer Behavior, Basic Concepts, 1977 (Box 32)
  - Virtuous Journalist, M. Kirkhorn, 1982 (Box 32)
  - What Do We Know About How Advertising Works?, T. Joyce, 1967 (Box 32)
  - What Is Multinationality, Can It Be Cured?, D. Lanigan, 1983 (Box 32)
  - What Jim Young Said - And What He Didn't Say, J. Bullmore, 1978 (Box 32)
  - What We Have Learned, J. Bullmore, 1984 (Box 32)
  - What We Have Learned About Managing Global Brands, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Why I Envy You Beginning Your Career at JWT, D. Lanigan, 1986 (Box 32)
  - James Young writings, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Zen and the Value of an Idling Engine, D. Johnston, 1984 (Box 32)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1984, 1 boxes
  [The following vinyl recordings were removed to the JWT Audiovisual Collection: The Christmas Sounds of San Francisco, 1966 Christmas Chorus, Johann Strauss 100th Anniversary Concert Produced by JWT, Vienna.]
  Conditions Governing Access note
  [Restrictions on Access: Cassettes need to be reformatted for patron use.]
  - World Advertising Forum audio cassettes
    - AV 1, J. Bullmore speech (Box 32)
    - AV 2, JWT Song (Box 32)
- Oversize Materials, 1970-1976, 2 boxes
  Includes large format items removed from previous series.
  - Client files (Box 33)
    - Kellogg's, Japan, packaging, 1970, 1976 (Box 33)
      [Includes Japanese cereal boxes for Corn Flakes, Frosted Flakes, Honey Smacks, and Corn Pops, among others.]
    - Lejaby, tear sheets, 1975-1976 (Box 33)
    - Pan American Airways, general, 1976 (Box 33)
    - Rustenberg Platinum Mines, creative, 1976 (Box 33)
  - International offices
    - Johannesburg, general, 1973-1974 (Box 33)
      [Includes organization chart.]
    - Mexico City, general, 1974 (Box 33)
      [Includes Ford brochure.]
    - International Area Renovation, 1974 (Box 34)
      [Includes floor plans.]